Just a Baby Boy.
Baby Boy is a crime, drama, romance film directed by John Singleton.
The story of Jody, a misguided, 20-year-old African-American who is really just a baby boy
finally forced-kicking and screaming to face the commitments of real life.
Streetwise and jobless, he has not only fathered two children by two different
women-Yvette and Peanut but still lives with his own mother.
He can't seem to strike a balance or find direction in his chaotic life.
Joseph Summers, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Yvette, played by Taraji P. Henson.
Sweetpea, played by Omar Gooding.
Melvin 'Mel', played by Ving Rhames.
Rodney, played by Snoop Dogg.
Juanita, played by A.J. Johnson.
Baby Boy is a 2001 American coming-of-age hood drama film directed, written and produced by John
Singleton, and starring Tyrese Gibson, Snoop Dogg, Ving Rhames, Omar Gooding, A.J.
Johnson and Taraji P.
The film follows Joseph "Jody" Summers (Gibson), a 20-year-old bike mechanic as he
lives and learns in his everyday life in the hood of Los Angeles.
The film was originally written with rapper-actor Tupac Shakur in mind to play
Jody; Shakur had previously worked with Singleton on Poetic Justice.
However, following Shakur's murder in 1996, Singleton decided to
replace Shakur with R&B artist Tyrese Gibson.
Additionally, the role of Rodney was originally written for Ice Cube, who had
worked with Singleton on Boyz n the Hood and Higher Learning.
The film marked the feature acting debut of Gibson and
provided Henson with her first prominent role.
Released in the United States on June 27, 2001, the film received predominantly positive reviews from
critics and audiences, with many deeming it as Singleton's best film since Boyz n the Hood.
The film is also the final feature film written by Singleton as he did not write any of his
later feature-length directorial projects before his death in April 2019.
The film explores themes of bootlegger, single
parent, intolerance, fistfight, condom.
The tone is emotional and intense.